<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>jay l. colbert</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/</link><description>Recent content on jay l. colbert</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilde-at-heart.garden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>7 Personal knowledge management could be the Modernist urge to reinforce Grand Narratives</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/7-personal-knowledge-management-could-be-the-modernist-urge-to-reinforce-grand-narratives/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/7-personal-knowledge-management-could-be-the-modernist-urge-to-reinforce-grand-narratives/</guid><description>In the quotation below, author David Foster Wallace touches on a core aspect of the Modernist movement of literature and art: there are Grand Narratives, inherent truths, that guide our lives. These narratives are &amp;ldquo;how things should be.&amp;rdquo; The chaos and disruption caused by WWI made it seem like those Grand Narratives were gone. Think of T.S. Eliot&amp;rsquo;s poem &amp;ldquo;The Waste Land,&amp;rdquo; a sort of Modernist interpretation of the Fisher King story.</description></item><item><title>7a Personal knowledge management can come from a state of play</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/7a-personal-knowledge-management-can-come-from-a-state-of-play/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/7a-personal-knowledge-management-can-come-from-a-state-of-play/</guid><description>Instead of personal knowledge management coming from the need to restore control over our attention and knowledge, it can come from the desire to explore and create. David Foster Wallace describes this as an &amp;ldquo;intellectual adventure.&amp;rdquo; We don&amp;rsquo;t restore meaning and patterns, we find them. Our relationship to information can be exploratory and curious.
For me &amp;ndash; I mean, a lot of the motivation had to do with, it seems to me, that so much of pre-millennial life in America consists of enormous amounts of what seem like discrete bits of information coming, and that the real kind of intellectual adventure is finding ways to relate them to each other and to find larger patterns and meanings, which of course is essentially narrative, but that structurally it&amp;rsquo;s a bit different.</description></item><item><title>1c What is left behind when you remove photos from a scrapbook?</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1c-what-is-left-behind-when-you-remove-photos-from-a-scrapbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1c-what-is-left-behind-when-you-remove-photos-from-a-scrapbook/</guid><description>During the [[055 - Feminist Scrapbooking]] episode of my podcast [[librarypunk]], we had on feminist scrapbooker Kristin Tweedale to talk about scrapbooking as a mode of information and knowledge management and how to do it in anti-capitalist ways.
One of us (I&amp;rsquo;m blanking on who) mentioned someone in the family having a scrapbook with all the pictures removed. Not only was the scrapbook empty, but it had once been full of photos that were no longer there.</description></item><item><title>6a3 Libraries lend the previous experiences of materials</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a3-libraries-lend-the-previous-experiences-of-materials/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a3-libraries-lend-the-previous-experiences-of-materials/</guid><description>The [[189 - Library Socialism &amp;amp; Usufruct]] episode of the [[Srsly Wrong]] podcast mentions that writing in library books is not defacing or destroying them; rather, &amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; is added because the library lends out the thoughts and scribbles of everyone who had that book before.
Even if an item hasn&amp;rsquo;t been scribbled in, the library, in theory, is still lending that item with its entire history of having been used and enjoyed by others.</description></item><item><title>til 2022-07-06 001</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-07-06-001/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-07-06-001/</guid><description>Zotero is usually pretty good at recognizing the format of something you save via the browser extension. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed it doesn&amp;rsquo;t pick up podcasts, even though that&amp;rsquo;s a format you can cite.
However! If you have the Zotero iPhone app, you can use the &amp;ldquo;share&amp;rdquo; function in your podcast app (Spotify, at least; I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested others) and send it to Zotero. It recognizes it as a podcast when done that way.</description></item><item><title>How I use the Logseq Readwise plugin in my Zettelkasten</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/how-i-use-the-logseq-readwise-plugin-in-my-zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/how-i-use-the-logseq-readwise-plugin-in-my-zettelkasten/</guid><description>The above image is the visualization of my Logseq graph, at least as of June 26th, 2022 at around 3:00 PM EDT. I know it&amp;rsquo;s not as pretty or big as some others you may have seen, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to see how I use Logseq, its linking capabilities, and its integrations.
You&amp;rsquo;ll see some clusters there in the center. That represents the reference notes, topic tags, and main notes of my Zettelkasten.</description></item><item><title>12 Favorite Questions</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/12-favorite-questions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/12-favorite-questions/</guid><description>How can I learn enough about algorithms and Clojure so I can create generative art without tutorials?
What do I need to know about Clojure?
What do I need to know about algorithms?
Fields
Voronoi
What do I need to know about composition?
What do I need to know about Quil?
What do I need to know about clojure2d?
How do I explore aesthetics in knowledge management?
How can I improve my thinking to make better decisions?</description></item><item><title>4a Opera queens are embodied personal information management</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/4a-opera-queens-are-embodied-personal-information-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/4a-opera-queens-are-embodied-personal-information-management/</guid><description>Opera queens (gay men who are fans of opera) collect the ephemera of opera to a degree which borders on hoarding: recordings, programs, pictures, signatures, interviews, memories, etc. There is no larger system by which they capture or organize this information, nor is there anything these men do with what they collect.
Instead of using personal knowledge management systems, opera queens are personal information management. They are the tool which captures information.</description></item><item><title>6a2 Scrapbooks are a visual, emergent, and generative self-archive of a person's life and memories</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a2-scrapbooks-are-a-visual-emergent-and-generative-self-archive-of-a-persons-life-and-memories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a2-scrapbooks-are-a-visual-emergent-and-generative-self-archive-of-a-persons-life-and-memories/</guid><description>As part of scrapbooking, scrapbookers capture and collect ephemera of the things they do throughout a day, week, month, or other chunk of time. They use scrapbooks to preserve memories. Archives are usually a collection of materials of an institution or person.
Scrapbooks, then, are the archives of a person where they are both the archivist and the person whose materials are being archived.
They have been metaphorically defined as &amp;ldquo;the secretions of an organism&amp;rdquo;, and are distinguished from documents that have been consciously written or created to communicate a particular message to posterity.</description></item><item><title>top of mind</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/top-of-mind/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/top-of-mind/</guid><description>Taken from Andy Matuschak:
Sort of like a /now page, but with a broader time horizon and focused on what I’m thinking about.
aesthetics and aesthetics of information
cyborgs, but in the assemblages sense
Portrayals of information sources, seeking, and transmission in books and film
rhizomes and Deleuze in general
sensuality in response to information and tools
spirituality and information</description></item><item><title>til 2022-06-19 001</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-06-19-001/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-06-19-001/</guid><description>Instead of putting a query in my daily template, I can generate a running list of fleeting notes via a default query. I can do the same for a running list of drafts to work on. In the default query section of config.edn:
{:title &amp;#34;💡 FLEETING&amp;#34; :query (and (property type fleeting) (not (property tags templates)) (not (task done))) :result-transform (fn [result] (sort-by (fn [h] (get h :block/created-at)) result)) :collapsed? true :breadcrumb-show?</description></item><item><title>5b We need an erotics of metadata</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5b-we-need-an-erotics-of-metadata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5b-we-need-an-erotics-of-metadata/</guid><description>Much of contemporary metadata scholarship focuses on the ethics of descriptive metadata, particularly classification systems. Rightly so. However, like Susan Sontag argues in her essay &amp;ldquo;Against Interpretation,&amp;rdquo; I think the focus on ethics and its effects on end users has become more important than the metadata and the labor of the library worker. Instead of purely focusing on ethics, we if we focused on aesthetics. What insights will the open up about the nature of metadata work?</description></item><item><title>6 Trusting our tools means trusting the people who built those tools</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6-trusting-our-tools-means-trusting-the-people-who-built-those-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6-trusting-our-tools-means-trusting-the-people-who-built-those-tools/</guid><description>Our digital tools and systems, like note-taking apps and search algorithms, are created by people. Our biases and ideologies are built into the tools. John M. Culkin follows this line of thought when giving a brief explanation of The Medium is the Message.
Life imitates art. We shape our tools and thereafter they shape us.1
So, when we trust tools built by other people, we are also trusting their biases and ideologies to shape us and our ideas.</description></item><item><title>6a Using a tool creates a sensual relationship between its user(s) and its creator(s)</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a-using-a-tool-creates-a-sensual-relationship-between-its-users-and-its-creators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a-using-a-tool-creates-a-sensual-relationship-between-its-users-and-its-creators/</guid><description>The aesthetics of a tool can bring us joy, discomfort, peace, or any number of emotional responses. People made the decisions about the user interface, the possible workflows, the graphics and design, etc. with, one would hope, the end-user in mind. These emotional responses happen in the body and have various sensual responses. Culkin, making a pun on message, likens our tools to massages because of how they affect our sensual experience.</description></item><item><title>6a1 The mind is also a tool which we trust and with which we have a sensual relationship</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a1-the-mind-is-also-a-tool-which-we-trust-and-with-which-we-have-a-sensual-relationship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/6a1-the-mind-is-also-a-tool-which-we-trust-and-with-which-we-have-a-sensual-relationship/</guid><description>Do we count our mind as a tool we created? Or is our mind a creator whom we must trust? Either way, the mind is embodied in our somatic responses to tools. Jon Greenaway explores this fact through the films of [[David Cronenberg]], stressing how the mind is not just embodied but extends beyond the body which contains it. When we trust the creators of tools, we are, at the core, trusting how their minds are embodied in and alter the physical world.</description></item><item><title>til 2022-06-13 001</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-06-13-001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/til-2022-06-13-001/</guid><description>When viewing a query in table view in Logseq, you can order the properties by toggling them off and toggling them back on in the order you want them to appear.</description></item><item><title>spirituality and information</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/spirituality-and-information/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/spirituality-and-information/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
I first started thinking about the relationship between spirituality and information when Kyle Courtney, the copyright librarian at Harvard, told me about an interaction he had with a Buddhist monk. Some monks were collaborating with Harvard to give texts to the library, I think. These texts go back to the Middle Ages, so of course they’re in the public domain, ready to be digitized.
Until one Monk said, “I wrote this one.</description></item><item><title>5a The aesthetics of information affects our relationships to it</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5a-the-aesthetics-of-information-affects-our-relationships-to-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5a-the-aesthetics-of-information-affects-our-relationships-to-it/</guid><description>The visual components of both information and how we interact with information (such as using arrows to draw connections in the quotation below) reinforce the sensual aspect of working with information, knowledge, and metadata. In particular, this person&amp;rsquo;s statement that they make their &amp;ldquo;thoughts hold hands&amp;rdquo; brings a physical and almost erotic element to how they visualize the network of their thinking.
i love arrows -&amp;gt; and drawing connections -&amp;gt; noticing patterns -&amp;gt; making my thoughts hold hands -&amp;gt;1</description></item><item><title>longing release</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/longing-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/longing-release/</guid><description>I made this piece as part of the &amp;ldquo;Concentrated Creativity&amp;rdquo; BASB alumni sprint.
It is a piece of generative art made with the Clojure programming language and the Quil and genartlib libraries. The base code is inspired by the Golden Ratio Flower by Jack Rusher.
The part of my code that actually draws the above is:
(def palette (cycle [[326 100 61] [0 0 0] [0 0 100]])) (def PHI (/ (+ 1 (Math/sqrt 5)) 2)) (defn gauss [mean variance] (+ mean (* variance (q/random-gaussian)))) (defn actual-draw [] ; art goes here (q/frame-rate 10) (q/no-stroke) (q/background 0 0 60) (q/with-translation [(w 0.</description></item><item><title>4 Creative works are cyborgs</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/4-creative-works-are-cyborgs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/4-creative-works-are-cyborgs/</guid><description>Nothing we make is truly original. All creative work is inspired by something, draws from something, builds on something.
As Tiago Forte says in the tweet below, creative work is assembled. Philosophically, assemblages are component parts brought together in a way that is fluid (not fixed). Donna Haraway uses the metaphor of [[cyborgs]]1 or &amp;ldquo;making kin&amp;rdquo;2 for assemblages: you bring together things that might not otherwise fit together instead of resolving the tensions between them.</description></item><item><title>5 Metadata work is a sensual experience</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5-metadata-work-is-a-sensual-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/5-metadata-work-is-a-sensual-experience/</guid><description>Interacting with information in any capacity triggers sensual responses and resonances in our bodies and minds (which are also our bodies). Metadata workers describe and organize knowledge and information. This requires tuning in to those pleasurable or otherwise sensual reactions as organizing principles.
I’ve come to think of the body as a computer, taking in more data from more sources than we could ever consciously consider. Our emotions are a vast subterranean intelligence, drawing on not only our senses, but the genetic memories of our ancestors and endless layers of communal thought.</description></item><item><title>1 Archival silence is a problem when its purpose is oppression</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1-archival-silence-is-a-problem-when-its-purpose-is-oppression/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1-archival-silence-is-a-problem-when-its-purpose-is-oppression/</guid><description>Those in power and who hold capital will destroy, distort, and otherwise purposefully not collect information and create metadata about those they wish to silence and remove from any sort of historical record.
the unintentional or purposeful absence or distortion of documentation of enduring value, resulting in gaps and inabilities to represent the past accurately.1
sprouted from archival silence [[@archival silence]] Dictionary of Archives Terminology&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>1a Archival silence is a good thing when its purpose is protection</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1a-archival-silence-is-a-good-thing-when-its-purpose-is-protection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1a-archival-silence-is-a-good-thing-when-its-purpose-is-protection/</guid><description>Having silences in our archives is good when people would be put in danger or have their privacy violated otherwise.
parent 1 Archival silence is a problem when its purpose is oppression See my presentation Describing Absence The Complicated Power of Metadata Surrogates in Libraries and Archives for specific examples and scenarios.</description></item><item><title>1a1 Archival silence is a tool</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1a1-archival-silence-is-a-tool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1a1-archival-silence-is-a-tool/</guid><description>Rather than being necessarily good or bad, archival silence is a tool. We should know when to wield it and when to fix when it happens.
parent 1a Archival silence is a good thing when its purpose is protection</description></item><item><title>1b Not all knowledge systems will hear archival silences the same way</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1b-not-all-knowledge-systems-will-hear-archival-silences-the-same-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/1b-not-all-knowledge-systems-will-hear-archival-silences-the-same-way/</guid><description>Not every culture, group, or community is going to have the same knowledge management, knowledge transmission, or knowledge organization systems as the dominant library/archival science framework. There are oral traditions of music transmission, there are Tibetan Buddhist practices that are only shared between lama and student in an unending lineage back to the Buddha, there are traditions where information is only shared within that group.
parent 1 Archival silence is a problem when its purpose is oppression</description></item><item><title>2 Metadata surrogates have more value than what they are surrogates of in a capitalist society</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2-metadata-surrogates-have-more-value-than-what-they-are-surrogates-of-in-a-capitalist-society/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2-metadata-surrogates-have-more-value-than-what-they-are-surrogates-of-in-a-capitalist-society/</guid><description>In a capitalist society, governments and corporations construct surrogates of us from the data they mine. And in a capitalist society, that data surrogate is more &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; and has more value than we do because it makes them money.
Therefore, it is not always a bad thing to have silences in our collections. Sometimes, those silences are necessary. See 1a Archival silence is a good thing when its purpose is protection</description></item><item><title>2a Metadata surrogates are inherently arborescent</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2a-metadata-surrogates-are-inherently-arborescent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2a-metadata-surrogates-are-inherently-arborescent/</guid><description>Metadata surrogates are the descriptive record which stands in for the &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; item being cataloged. In this case, the &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; item would be the seed and the surrogate would be what grows and branches out from that original item. The surrogate is a representation of the original item.
In A Thousand Plateaus, Deleuze and Guattari name arborescence or the model of the tree as the paradigm for knowledge and practice in the modern Western world; in this model, a small idea—a seed or acorn—takes root and grows into a tree with a sturdy trunk supporting numerous branches, all linked to and traceable back to the original seed.</description></item><item><title>2a1 Metadata surrogates are the tree trunk instead of the end of a branch</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2a1-metadata-surrogates-are-the-tree-trunk-instead-of-the-end-of-a-branch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/2a1-metadata-surrogates-are-the-tree-trunk-instead-of-the-end-of-a-branch/</guid><description>When constructed by others in order to exploit us, the metadata surrogates of ourselves are the seed or original instead of being the thing that grows from and represents the original item.
parent 2a Metadata surrogates are inherently arborescent</description></item><item><title>3 My transsexual body is a metadata record</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/3-my-transsexual-body-is-a-metadata-record/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/3-my-transsexual-body-is-a-metadata-record/</guid><description>If metadata is the sum total of what can be said about any information object at any given time, then the bodies of trans people undergoing medical forms of transition are living, always-changing metadata records. They are the information object, and they are also what can be said about the information object.
My transsexual body is a catalog, a finding aid, of every testosterone injection I have given myself in my thigh, of the parts of my body I have willingly destroyed to create something better in their wake, of the process of teaching myself to shave my face (which is way different than shaving your legs, it turns out), of the ways my sexuality changed, of the hours of speech and movement therapy I did, of the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m still afraid to use gendered bathrooms in public after 4 years.</description></item><item><title>Describing Absence The Complicated Power of Metadata Surrogates in Libraries and Archives</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/describing-absence-the-complicated-power-of-metadata-surrogates-in-libraries-and-archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/describing-absence-the-complicated-power-of-metadata-surrogates-in-libraries-and-archives/</guid><description>These are the speaker notes of a talk I gave at the New Hampshire Archives Group Spring 2022 Workshop on [[May 17th, 2022]]
Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you for coming to my presentation when you could just leave and go outside. My name is Jay L. Colbert, and today I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;Describing Absence: The Complicated Power of Metadata Surrogates in Libraries &amp;amp; Archives&amp;rdquo;
Advanced notice that this presentation will mention suicide and potentially upsetting language.</description></item><item><title>archives and attics</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archives-and-attics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archives-and-attics/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
There seems to be a popular belief that an archive is where you put things you don&amp;rsquo;t need anymore. They remain there, safe for when you need them, but they require no maintenance. In our personal knowledge management systems, in our code bases, wherever, you just throw things in there.
That is not an archive. That is an attic.
Archives require maintenance, care, and intention. They require workers who catalog the materials of people and institutions.</description></item><item><title>my digital garden is rhizomatic</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/my-digital-garden-is-rhizomatic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/my-digital-garden-is-rhizomatic/</guid><description>🌿 budding and almost ready to split into Zettels
My note seedlings don&amp;rsquo;t take root and branch off, with branches returning to a single point (the trunk of the tree). My note seedlings are, instead, rhizomes. The notes and ideas don&amp;rsquo;t have one origin point. &amp;ldquo;Branches can grow out of any spot towards any direction.&amp;rdquo;1
“Rhizomes, however, do not function according to representation. Nothing in a rhizome represents something else. There are only connections.</description></item><item><title>archival silence</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archival-silence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archival-silence/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
archival silence the unintentional or purposeful absence or distortion of documentation of enduring value, resulting in gaps and inabilities to represent the past accurately[^1] In particular, archival silence often happens in collections relating to Indigenous people and enslaved people. How do we ethically describe resources about people we have power over, historically or otherwise, if information about them was never never collected? How do we bring attention to these silences?</description></item><item><title>Obligatory "I Took the Building a Second Brain Course" Post</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</guid><description>Every time I search a note-taking tool online, I inevitably see it: &amp;ldquo;Using insert-tool-here to build my second brain&amp;rdquo; or some variation on that theme. The video or blog post will always go over the basics of what a second brain is, and it usually mentions that the person took Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s Building a Second Brain course.
So I guess it&amp;rsquo;s my turn.
What is Building a Second Brain Building a Second Brain is a methodology, online course, and (as of writing this post) forthcoming book by Tiago Forte.</description></item><item><title>about</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/about/</guid><description>about me My name is Jay, and I&amp;rsquo;m a librarian. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about knowledge management and organization, personal or otherwise, and I&amp;rsquo;m a nerd for anything hypertext. I also love opera and my two pets: my cat King Arthur and my bearded dragon Coop.
about this site This is a 🍀 digital garden. It contains my notes on various things I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. These notes are at various stages of growth.</description></item><item><title>digital garden</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/digital-garden/</guid><description>What is a digital garden? To quote Maggie Appleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;A Brief History &amp;amp; Ethos of the Digital Garden&amp;rdquo;,
They&amp;rsquo;re not following the conventions of the &amp;ldquo;personal blog,&amp;rdquo; as we&amp;rsquo;ve come to know it. Rather than presenting a set of polished articles, displayed in reverse chronological order, these sites act more like free form, work-in-progress wikis.
A garden is a collection of evolving ideas that aren&amp;rsquo;t strictly organised by their publication date.</description></item><item><title>personal knowledge management</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/personal-knowledge-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/personal-knowledge-management/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
For all of human history knowledge has been controlled and held by the elite and powerful and privileged. —Carrie Ben-Ysrael
When we have control over how we relate to information and knowledge, that can be a radical act.
When others control our relationship to information, it shapes our reality in ways we might not notice. It also affects how we construct the social identities of ourselves and others.1</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/zettelkasten/</guid><description>What is a Zettelkasten? In German, Zettelkasten means &amp;ldquo;slip box.&amp;rdquo; It is both a method of personal knowledge management and a physical (or digital) system you maintain. The method was popularized by German scholar Niklas Luhmann who used it as a &amp;ldquo;conversation partner&amp;rdquo; to help write hundreds of articles and books. To create a Zettelkasten, you need two compartments: literature notes and Zettels. Literature notes are just bibliographic information. Niklas Luhmann wrote the citations of resources on index cards.</description></item></channel></rss>