<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>blog on jay l. colbert</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on jay l. colbert</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilde-at-heart.garden/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I am in here Part 1—What I Learned From Reading Infinite Jest in 92 Days</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/i-am-in-here-part-1-what-i-learned-from-reading-infinite-jest-in-92-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/i-am-in-here-part-1-what-i-learned-from-reading-infinite-jest-in-92-days/</guid><description>I lived a lifetime reading Infinite Jest.
The book, by David Foster Wallace, is 1,079 pages long. Approximately 100 pages of that are endnotes. No, you can&amp;rsquo;t skip them.
It was one of the easiest reading experiences of my life.
Well, kind of.
When I say I lived a lifetime reading the book, I mean a few things:
I went through a lot spiritually, emotionally, and mentally during.
My first attempt was between my sophomore and junior years of college.</description></item><item><title>My Zettelkasten workflow from start to finish</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/my-zettelkasten-workflow-from-start-to-finish/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/my-zettelkasten-workflow-from-start-to-finish/</guid><description>Two things are very important to me:
Documenting my workflows. Sharing my knowledge with others as freely as possible. As of time of writing, I&amp;rsquo;m participating in some &amp;ldquo;learning sprints&amp;rdquo; for queries in Logseq. I actually don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself a Logseq power user or anything, at least compared to the folks who build these complicated dashboards and workflows for every aspect of their lives. I mainly use Logseq for my Zettelkasten; therefore, my needs aren&amp;rsquo;t too complicated.</description></item><item><title>How I use the Logseq Readwise plugin in my Zettelkasten</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/how-i-use-the-logseq-readwise-plugin-in-my-zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/how-i-use-the-logseq-readwise-plugin-in-my-zettelkasten/</guid><description>The above image is the visualization of my Logseq graph, at least as of June 26th, 2022 at around 3:00 PM EDT. I know it&amp;rsquo;s not as pretty or big as some others you may have seen, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to see how I use Logseq, its linking capabilities, and its integrations.
You&amp;rsquo;ll see some clusters there in the center. That represents the reference notes, topic tags, and main notes of my Zettelkasten.</description></item><item><title>Describing Absence The Complicated Power of Metadata Surrogates in Libraries and Archives</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/describing-absence-the-complicated-power-of-metadata-surrogates-in-libraries-and-archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/describing-absence-the-complicated-power-of-metadata-surrogates-in-libraries-and-archives/</guid><description>These are the speaker notes of a talk I gave at the New Hampshire Archives Group Spring 2022 Workshop on [[May 17th, 2022]]
Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you for coming to my presentation when you could just leave and go outside. My name is Jay L. Colbert, and today I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting &amp;ldquo;Describing Absence: The Complicated Power of Metadata Surrogates in Libraries &amp;amp; Archives&amp;rdquo;
Advanced notice that this presentation will mention suicide and potentially upsetting language.</description></item><item><title>Obligatory "I Took the Building a Second Brain Course" Post</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</guid><description>Every time I search a note-taking tool online, I inevitably see it: &amp;ldquo;Using insert-tool-here to build my second brain&amp;rdquo; or some variation on that theme. The video or blog post will always go over the basics of what a second brain is, and it usually mentions that the person took Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s Building a Second Brain course.
So I guess it&amp;rsquo;s my turn.
What is Building a Second Brain Building a Second Brain is a methodology, online course, and (as of writing this post) forthcoming book by Tiago Forte.</description></item></channel></rss>