<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Pages on jay l. colbert</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on jay l. colbert</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>archives and attics</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archives-and-attics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archives-and-attics/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
There seems to be a popular belief that an archive is where you put things you don&amp;rsquo;t need anymore. They remain there, safe for when you need them, but they require no maintenance. In our personal knowledge management systems, in our code bases, wherever, you just throw things in there.
That is not an archive. That is an attic.
Archives require maintenance, care, and intention. They require workers who catalog the materials of people and institutions.</description></item><item><title>archival silence</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archival-silence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/archival-silence/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
archival silence
n.
the unintentional or purposeful absence or distortion of documentation of enduring value, resulting in gaps and inabilities to represent the past accurately1 In particular, archival silence often happens in collections relating to Indigenous people and enslaved people.
How do we ethically describe resources about people we have power over, historically or otherwise, if information about them was never never collected? How do we bring attention to these silences?</description></item><item><title>Obligatory "I Took the Building a Second Brain Course" Post</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/obligatory-i-took-the-building-a-second-brain-course-post/</guid><description>Every time I search a note-taking tool online, I inevitably see it: &amp;ldquo;Using insert-tool-here to build my second brain&amp;rdquo; or some variation on that theme. The video or blog post will always go over the basics of what a second brain is, and it usually mentions that the person took Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s Building a Second Brain course.
So I guess it&amp;rsquo;s my turn.
What is Building a Second Brain Building a Second Brain is a methodology, online course, and (as of writing this post) forthcoming book by Tiago Forte.</description></item><item><title>about</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/about/</guid><description>about me My name is Jay, and I&amp;rsquo;m a librarian. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about knowledge management and organization, personal or otherwise, and I&amp;rsquo;m a nerd for anything hypertext. I also love opera and my two pets: my cat King Arthur and my bearded dragon Coop.
about this site This is a 🍀 digital garden. It contains my notes on various things I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. These notes are at various stages of growth.</description></item><item><title>digital garden</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/digital-garden/</guid><description>What is a digital garden? To quote Maggie Appleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;A Brief History &amp;amp; Ethos of the Digital Garden&amp;rdquo;,
They&amp;rsquo;re not following the conventions of the &amp;ldquo;personal blog,&amp;rdquo; as we&amp;rsquo;ve come to know it. Rather than presenting a set of polished articles, displayed in reverse chronological order, these sites act more like free form, work-in-progress wikis.
A garden is a collection of evolving ideas that aren&amp;rsquo;t strictly organised by their publication date.</description></item><item><title>personal knowledge management</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/personal-knowledge-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/personal-knowledge-management/</guid><description>🌱 seedling
For all of human history knowledge has been controlled and held by the elite and powerful and privileged. —Carrie Ben-Ysrael
When we have control over how we relate to information and knowledge, that can be a radical act.
When others control our relationship to information, it shapes our reality in ways we might not notice. It also affects how we construct the social identities of ourselves and others.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilde-at-heart.garden/pages/zettelkasten/</guid><description>What is a Zettelkasten? In German, Zettelkasten means &amp;ldquo;slip box.&amp;rdquo; It is both a method of personal knowledge management and a physical (or digital) system you maintain. The method was popularized by German scholar Niklas Luhmann who used it as a &amp;ldquo;conversation partner&amp;rdquo; to help write hundreds of articles and books. To create a Zettelkasten, you need two compartments: literature notes and Zettels. Literature notes are just bibliographic information. Niklas Luhmann wrote the citations of resources on index cards.</description></item></channel></rss>